Welcome. In the last lecture, we successfully ended the locomotion for our climbing. Now
欢迎。在上一次讲座中，我们成功地结束了攀登的运动。现在
we can climb up, down, left and right. Now before we move on, there's small issue that
我们可以向上、向下、向左和向右爬。在我们继续前进之前，有一个小问题
I'd like to fix. So for my climb left and right, there's still a bit of sliding happening.
我想修正一下。在我向左和向右爬的过程中，仍然有一些滑动发生。
And the reason for that is, the starting position of those two animations is not the same as
其原因是，这两个动画的起始位置和我们的空闲动画不一样。
our idle animation. And I'd like to fix that. So go back to my animation folder, open this
我们的空闲动画。而我想解决这个问题。所以回到我的动画文件夹，打开这个
adjusted, double click to open this left adjusted, double click to open this right adjusted,
调整，双击打开这个左调整，双击打开这个右调整、
click pause. So right now for my animations, they are a bit lower than the idle animation.
点击暂停。所以现在对于我的动画来说，它们比空闲动画要低一些。
So I need to lift them up a little bit. To something like this, click add key. And for
所以我需要把它们抬高一点。对这样的东西，点击添加键。而对于
this left, click pause and lift this one up a little bit. So something like this should
左边这个，点击暂停，把这个抬高一点。所以像这样的事情应该
do click add key and click play. I'm going to test it. So move to the right. Maybe I'll
点击添加键，然后点击播放。我准备测试一下。所以移到右边。也许我将
need a little bit more. So go back to this left, lift it up a little bit more. Something
需要更多一点。所以回到这个左边，再往上提一点。一些
like this, click add key. For this right, lift it up a little bit more, add key and
像这样，点击添加钥匙。对于这个右边，再把它抬起来一点，添加钥匙，然后
click play again. Yeah, something like that. Now I think their positions are the same.
再点击播放。是的，类似这样。现在我认为他们的位置是一样的。
And just like so, I think this is looking much better. We're going to fix the hands and
就像这样，我认为这看起来好多了。我们要用控制耙来修正手和
the feet placement later using control rake. So don't worry about that. And the next feature
脚的位置，然后使用控制耙。所以不用担心这个问题。而下一个功能
that I like to add, so we can climb to the left and climb to the right. We can climb
所以我们可以向左和向右爬行。我们可以爬
up and climb down. The thing that I want to do, so when the character has reached the
上爬和下爬。我想做的事情是，当角色到达地面时，比如说在这里附近，我想退出。
floor, say somewhere near here, I want to exit the clamp state automatically. Right
地板，比如说在这里附近，我想自动退出钳制状态。对
now we'll need to press F to do that manually. And I like to automate this process. Luckily
现在我们需要按F键来手动操作。而我喜欢把这个过程自动化。幸运的是
for us, without current app, that's something really easy to do. So I'm going to close my
对我们来说，没有当前的应用程序，这是很容易做到的事情。所以我将关闭我的
project, go back to Visual Studio. I'm going to go back to my custom movement component
项目，回到Visual Studio。我将回到我的自定义运动组件
dot H and I'm going to scroll up. So under the function check should stop climbing. I'm
点H，我将向上滚动。所以在功能检查下应该停止爬行。我将
going to create another function. It's going to return a blow as well. I'm going to call
将创建另一个函数。它也将返回一个打击。我将调用
this function check has reached floor and I'm going to create a function definition under
这个函数检查已经到达地面，我将在这个函数下创建一个函数定义
this check should stop climbing. And I'm going to place the function in here. So instead
这个检查应该停止爬升。我将把这个函数放在这里。因此，代替
of this function, same as our climb trace, I'm going to use a capsule trace, but this
这个函数，和我们的爬升追踪一样，我将使用一个胶囊追踪，但这次我将追踪到
time I'm going to trace down to see if the character has reached the floor. And by doing
这次我要向下追踪，看看角色是否已经到达地面。而通过这样做
so we'll be also taking into the situation when the climbable surface isn't completely
这样做，我们也会考虑到当可攀爬的表面不是完全
flat into account. You'll know what I'm talking about very soon. So I'm going to delete this
平的情况。你很快就会知道我在说什么了。所以我将删除这
line and same as our climb trace, we'll need a start and an end. So first I'm going to
行，和我们的爬升轨迹一样，我们需要一个开始和一个结束。所以我首先要做的是
create a const F vector. I'm going to call this down vector and it's going to equal to
创建一个常量F矢量。我将把这个称为下降矢量，它将等于
update the component, get up vector. And I'm going to inverse this up vector. So this is
更新分量，得到向上的向量。然后我将反转这个向上的矢量。所以这就是
our down vector and I'm going to create another const F vector. I'm going to call this start
我将创建另一个常量F向量。我将把这个称为开始
offset. And it's going to equal to this down vector multiply with our heart code value of
偏移。它将等于这个下行向量乘以我们的心脏代码值
50 units. So this is our trace start offset. Then I'm going to create a const F vector.
50个单位。所以这就是我们的追踪起始偏移。然后我将创建一个常量F向量。
I'm going to call this one start and it's going to equal to this updated component, get
我将调用这个开始，它将等于这个更新的分量，得到
component location. And I'm going to plus this start offset. So this is our capsule trace
分量的位置。我将加上这个起始偏移。所以这就是我们的胶囊追踪
start. And I'm going to create another one. This will be the end and it's going to equal
开始。我还将创建另一个。这将是终点，它将等于
to start plus down vector. All right, we have the start and the end. Next thing I'm going
开始加向下的矢量。好了，我们有了起点和终点。接下来，我将会
to call the function do capsule trace multi by object and pass in this start the end.
调用do capsule trace multi by object这个函数，并把这个start和end传进去。
And for this draw debug shape, I'm going to pass in true. So we'll be drawing the shape
对于这个绘制调试形状，我将传入true。所以我们将在每一帧画出这个形状
every frame and I'm going to store the return result of this function inside of a local
我将把这个函数的返回结果存储在一个局部的
variable. So it's going to be a t array of type of hit result. I'm going to call this
变量内。所以它将是一个t数组类型的命中结果。我将把这个称为
possible floor hits. And first thing I'm going to check. So if this possible floor hits is
可能的楼层命中。我首先要检查的是。所以如果这个可能的楼层命中率是
empty, then I'm going to return false. So once we get past this if check, I'm going to loop
是空的，那么我将会返回false。所以一旦我们通过了这个if检查，我就会在这个数组中循环
through this array. So it's going to be a range based for loop. It'll be a const F hit
通过这个数组。所以这将是一个基于范围的for循环。这将是一个 const F hit
result reference. I'm going to call this possible floor hit and I'm going to look through this
结果的引用。我将调用这个可能的楼层命中，我将通过这个
array. So when we have reached the floor, very likely we'll have two hits. One hit is for
数组。因此，当我们已经达到地板时，很可能我们会有两个命中。一个命中是针对
the climbable surface and another hit is the floor. So I like to filter out the floor hit
一个是可攀爬的表面，另一个是地板。所以我喜欢过滤掉地板上的点击
and that's something we can use the hit impact normal to do. So I'm going to use the function
这就是我们可以用撞击法则来做的事情。所以我将使用函数
inside of F vector is called parallel. So I'm going to check if this possible floor
里面的F向量被称为平行。所以我将检查这个可能的地板是否
hit the impact normal. I'm going to inverse it. So if this inverse impact normal is parallel
撞击法线。我将对它进行反演。所以，如果这个反向的冲击法线与这个F向量、向上的向量平行
with this F vector, up vector, then this should be our floor. Here I'm assuming the normal
与这个F向量，向上的向量平行，那么这就应该是我们的地板。这里我假设可行走楼层的法线
of the walkable floor is always facing up. Depending on the geometry in your level, you
的法线总是朝上。根据你的关卡中的几何形状，你
can use a dot product here to do more specific checks. At this point, I'm confident that
你可以在这里使用点积来做更具体的检查。在这一点上，我相信
you know how to do it by yourself. So this is the first check. So the second check. So
你知道如何自己做。所以这是第一个检查。所以是第二个检查。所以
if our get unrotated climb velocity dot Z is less than negative 10 units. So here I'm
如果我们得到的未旋转的爬升速度点Z小于负10单位。所以我在这里
confirming if we are indeed moving down. When we first start climbing, we'll have a valid
确认我们是否确实在向下移动。当我们第一次开始爬升时，我们会有一个有效的
floor hit, but we shouldn't be able to exit the climb state since we are not moving down.
地面，但我们不应该能够退出爬升状态，因为我们没有向下移动。
Alright I'm going to store the result of this inside of a const local boolean. I'm going
好了，我要把这个结果存储在一个常量的本地布尔值中。我打算
to call this B floor reached. So if this B floor reached is true, I'm going to return
来调用这个B层达到。所以，如果这个B层达到了真，我将在这里返回
true in here. Outside of this for loop, I'm going to return false. Alright I'm going to
true在这里。在这个for循环之外，我将返回false。好了，我将会
compile first to see if there are any errors. I have a successful compile. Now I'm going
先编译一下，看看是否有什么错误。我有一个成功的编译。现在我将
to call the function. So copy this function and scroll up to this physics climb. I'm just
来调用这个函数。所以，复制这个函数，然后向上滚动到这个物理学爬升。我只是
going to print a debug message L for now. So if this has reached the floor is true,
现在要打印一个调试信息L。所以，如果这个已经到达地板是真的、
I'm going to print a message that says floor reached. And the color is going to be of color
我就会打印一条信息，说是已经到达地面。颜色将是
green. The key is going to be one. And in the else case, so if the condition is false, then
绿色。键值为1。而在其他情况下，如果条件是假的，那么
I'm going to say floor not reached. And I'm going to change the color to red. Alright
我就会说没有达到地板。我将把颜色改成红色。好的
I'm going to launch my editor back to see if this actually works. Go back to my editor,
我将启动我的编辑器，看看这是否真的有用。回到我的编辑器、
I'm going to press play in here. Then I'm going to press F. So you can see when we first
我将在这里按播放键。然后我按下F键。
start climbing, we have a valid floor hit. But since we are not moving down, here it
开始爬升时，我们有一个有效的楼层点击。但由于我们没有向下移动，这里
says floor not reached. Great, this is what we want. I'm going to move up a little bit
说未到达楼层。很好，这就是我们想要的。我将会向上移动一点儿
then move down. And you can see for a few frames there it says floor reached. I'm going
然后向下移动。你可以看到有几帧显示已经到达底线。我将
to try again. And move down. Floor reached. Great, this is working. And all that's left
再试一次。然后向下移动。到达楼层。很好，这是在工作。而剩下的
there to do is to actually call the function stop climbing. And I like to do that inside
要做的就是实际调用停止攀登的函数。而我喜欢在
of this function. So if check should stop climbing is true, or check has reached the
这个函数中进行。所以，如果检查应该停止攀爬为真，或者检查已经到达
floor is true, either way I'm going to stop climbing. I'm going to delete this debug function.
为真，无论如何，我都要停止攀爬。我将删除这个调试函数。
Then I'm going to use live coding. So press control plus shift plus S to save all, then
然后我将使用实时编码。所以按control加shift加S来保存所有，然后
control plus O plus F11 to trigger the live coding. All right, live coding succeeded.
控制键加O键加F11来触发实时编码。好的，实时编码成功了。
I'm going to test it again. So press play and enter the climb state, move up and move
我准备再测试一下。所以按播放，进入爬升状态，向上移动，移动
down. And just like that, we can exit the climb state. Great, this is working as expected.
下来。就这样，我们可以退出爬升状态。很好，这是在按照预期工作。
And there's one issue that I like to fix. You can see when we are exiting the climb state,
还有一个问题，我想解决。你可以看到当我们退出爬升状态的时候、
we are inside of that climb drop animation. That's not really too ideal. So the thing
我们是在爬升下降动画中。这真的不是太理想。所以我希望
that I want is when we have reached the floor, I want to transition into the for loop state
我想要的是，当我们到达地面时，我想过渡到for loop状态
directly. And there's something we can do inside of our animation blueprint. So go back
直接进入。我们可以在我们的动画蓝图中做一些事情。所以请回到
to this app. I'm going to go back to this full body. So between this climb drop and
到这个应用程序。我将回到这个全身。所以在这个爬升下降和
this for loop, I like to add in another condition. So drag out another pin connected to here.
循环之间，我喜欢添加另一个条件。所以拖出另一个针脚连接到这里。
If later for some reason, when you do this, you cannot see the newly added condition.
如果后来由于某种原因，当你这样做时，你不能看到新添加的条件。
You can just double click to open the condition that you have, then go back to this full body.
你可以双击来打开你的条件，然后回到这个完整的主体。
You should be able to see the condition. I believe this is a bug in 5.1. So I'm going
你应该能够看到这个条件。我相信这是在5.1中的一个错误。所以我打算
to open this new condition. And under this reference, I'm going to hold down control
打开这个新的条件。在这个参考条件下，我将按住控制键
and drag out this ground speed. I know I've named it ground speed, but if we're moving
并拖出这个地面速度。我知道我把它命名为地面速度，但如果我们在空中移动
in the air, we'll have some valid values for this variable. So I'm going to do an if check.
但如果我们在空中移动，我们会有一些有效的变量值。所以我打算做一个if检查。
If this ground speed is greater than zero, connect this to can enter transition. Then
如果这个地面速度大于零，就把这个连接到可以进入过渡。然后
if this is true, I'm going to enter this for loop state. All right. I'm going to click
如果这是真的，我将进入这个for循环状态。好的。我将会点击
compile and go back to my level, click play, press F, exit the climb state. And just like
编译，回到我的关卡，点击播放，按F，退出爬升状态。就这样
that, we can transition directly into the for loop state. How cool is that? And now we
就这样，我们可以直接过渡到for loop状态。这多酷啊？而现在我们
can climb up, we can climb down. When we have reached the floor, we can exit the climb state.
可以往上爬，可以往下爬。当我们到达地面时，我们可以退出攀爬状态。
Great. This is working really well. To detect the floor, I use a capsule to trace
很好。这工作真的很好。为了检测地板，我使用了一个胶囊来追踪
downwards and among those hit results, I checked if there is a valid floor hit. And if there
追踪，并且在这些撞击结果中，我检查是否有一个有效的地板撞击。而如果有
is, we can transition to this for loop directly. This shouldn't be too hard for you to implement
是，我们可以直接过渡到这个for循环。这对你来说应该不难实现
by yourself. Feel free to refer back to the video if you need help. And I'll see you
自己实现。如果你需要帮助，可以随时回看视频。我将在
in the next lecture.
在下一个讲座中见。
[Music]
[音乐]